Martha Graham Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Writings by and about Martha Graham (Box 224-228; 306)
  - Interviews (Box 226)
    - Madoff Enterprises interview with Martha Graham Interview fragments Interview, undated Interview, 15 December 1989 and 17 December 1989 Interview, 10 January 1989 Interview Nathan Kroll and Martha Graham, 6-7 December 1971 Interview with Bianca Jagger, 15 March 1990 Interview with Ron Protas (fragment, undated) Interview with Ron Protas (?) (fragments, undated) Interview with "Ruth," November 1951 (Box-folder 226/8)
  - Writings about Martha Graham (Authors Unidentified) (Box 227)
    Poems, writings, and scripts sent to Graham or contained in her papers (authors unidentified).
    - “A Note on Martha Graham’s Symbolism,” no author, n.d. “The Aesthetic of Martha Graham,” no author, n.d. “Martha Graham ‘In the American Grain,’” no author, n.d. “About Martha Graham,” no author, n.d. “For Martha Graham,” no author, n.d. “Scenario for Martha Graham,” no author, n.d. “Martha Graham est un novatrice...” no author, n.d. “Martha Graham fait figure de preue sur...” no author, n.d. “She is Priestess of Intellectual Ballet,” 1947 (fragment) R ́esume for Martha Graham (Box-folder 227/1)
    - “Decor for Hysteria,” no author, n.d. “Luke Tanner’s Daughter,” no author, n.d. “Poem: A Cambodian Dancer,” no author, n.d. “Phenomenal Woman,” no author, n.d. “The Mills of the Gods Grind Slow,” no author, n.d. “Marie Wigman, Danseuse Faustienne,” chapter 2 of unknown book manuscript, 1972. (Box-folder 227/2)
    - “When the Pale Unraveling Brain Falls from Ariadne’s Anxious Hand,” no author, n.d. Lear, Edward. “The Owl and the Pussy Cat Went to Sea,” n.d. “An Alpha of Insight,” no author, n.d. “Reflections on Dance,” no author, n.d. “Prelude and Exhortation, 1936,” no author, n.d. “Directions and Suggestions concerning the Canto Hondo and its Percussion,” no author, n.d. “Speaking of Pictures...Dancers,” Life, 1938. “European Martha Graham Workshop of Contemporary Dance,” in Danzare, 1988 Collection of Poems by Jean’s Fourth Grade, n.d. (Box-folder 227/3)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 227-228, 306)
    - Fragments, quotes, unidentified manuscripts (Box-folder 227/4)
    - Notes/drafts for Blood Memory (Box-folder 227/5)
    - Notes/drafts for Blood Memory (Box-folder 227/6)
    - Notes/drafts for Blood Memory (Box-folder 227/7)
    - Notes/drafts for Blood Memory (Box-folder 227/8)
    - Notes, Martha, the Musical (Box-folder 227/9)
    - “Beauty and the Buckskins” and “Mahanttan Corner” by D.C. Glover, Jr., 1952, Sheet music sent to Graham. (Box-folder 228/1)
    - Barnes, Clive. “The Cold War in Modern-Dance,” in The New York Times Magazine, July 28, 1968. (Box-folder 228/2)
    - Dreyer, Martin, “Foot Loose and Fancy,” in Houston Chronicle, Texas Magazine, Sunday, January 24, 1971. (Box-folder 228/3)
    - Fragments of writings in the hand of Martha Graham (Restricted) (Box-folder 306/1)
- Programs (Box 201-202)
  The Programs series contains a selection of programs that span the 1930s to 2003. A significant number of programs are also contained in the Scrapbooks series.
  - 1930s (xerox copies) (Box-folder 201/1)
  - 1940; 1941; 1947; 1940s undated (Box-folder 201/2)
  - 1949 (Box-folder 201/3)
  - 1950s (Box-folder 201/4)
  - 1960s (Box-folder 201/5)
  - 1971; 1973; 1974 (Box-folder 201/6)
  - 1975 (Box-folder 201/7)
  - 1976 (Box-folder 201/8)
  - 1978; 1979 (Box-folder 201/9)
  - 1984; 1985 (Box-folder 202/1)
  - 1986 (Box-folder 202/2)
  - 1987 (Box-folder 202/3)
  - 1988 (Box-folder 202/4)
  - 1990s; 2003 (Box-folder 202/5)
  - Programs, undated (Box-folder 202/6)
  - Drafts of programs; notes for programs; corrections for programs (Box-folder 202/7)
  - Drafts of programs; notes for programs; corrections for programs (Box-folder 202/8)
  - Drafts of programs; notes for programs; corrections for programs (Box-folder 202/9)
  - Programs and flyers, non-Graham (Box-folder 202/10)
- Business Papers (Box 278-305)
  The Business Papers series of the Martha Graham Dance Company; Martha Graham School of Contemporary Dance; and Martha Graham Center of Contemporary Dance consists of financial information that spans 1941 to 1993, including payroll and salary information; bank statements; deposit information; checkbook stubs; cancelled checks; budget information; purchase orders and invoices; and tax information. To view the materials in this series, please consult the curator of dance.
  - Martha Graham Dance Company (Box 278-281)
    - Invoices, 1941 (Box-folder 278/1)
    - Checkbook stubs, 1942 (Box-folder 278/2)
    - Receipts and invoices, 1944 (Box-folder 278/3-7)
    - Cancelled checks, 1944 April 24 – June 2 (Box-folder 278/8)
    - Bank statements and cancelled checks, 1944 (Box-folder 278/9)
    - Receipts and invoices, 1944 (Box-folder 278/10)
    - Payroll book, 1944 (Box-folder 279/1)
    - Payroll book, 1945 (Box-folder 279/2)
    - Cancelled checks, 1945 (Box-folder 279/3)
    - Check stubs, 1945 (Box-folder 279/4)
    - Petty cash receipts, 1945 (Box-folder 279/6)
    - Receipts and invoices, 1945 (Box-folder 279/7-8)
    - Payroll book, 1946 (Box-folder 280/1)
    - Cancelled checks, 1946 (Box-folder 280/2)
    - Payroll book, 1947 (Box-folder 280/3)
    - Profit and loss statements, 1942-1947 (Box-folder 280/4)
    - Payroll book, 1948 (Box-folder 281/1)
    - Checkbook/stubs, 1948 (Box-folder 281/2)
    - Salary list, 1948 (Box-folder 281/3)
    - New York City season budgets, 1948 (Box-folder 281/4)
    - Box office and ticket information, New York City season, February 1948 (Box-folder 281/5)
    - Invoices – William’s Theatrical Haulage, Inc., New York City season, February 1948 (Box-folder 281/6)
    - Payroll book, 1949 (Box-folder 281/7)
    - Budget information, 1949 (Box-folder 281/8)
  - Martha Graham Dance Company (MGDC) and Martha Graham School of Contemporary Dance (MGSCD) (Box 283)
    - Cash dispersements, MGDC, 1947-1950 (Box-folder 283/1)
    - Cash dispersements, MGSCD, 1949-1952 (Box-folder 283/2)
  - Martha Graham Dance Company (Box 282, 287)
    - Checkbook/stubs, 1949 April 1-1950 June 7 (Box-folder 282/1)
    - Payroll book, 1950 (Box-folder 282/2)
    - Bank statements and cancelled checks, 1950 (Box-folder 282/3)
    - Checkbook, 1950 (Box-folder 282/4)
    - Budget information, 1950 (Box-folder 282/5)
    - Checkbook/stubs, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 287/1)
    - Checkbook/stubs, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 287/2)
    - Cancelled checks, 1950 (Box-folder 287/3)
    - Budget information, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 287/4)
  - Martha Graham School of Contemporary Dance (Box 288)
    - Checkbook/stubs, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 288/1-2)
    - Cancelled checks, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 288/3)
    - Cancelled checks/bank statements, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 288/4)
    - Cancelled checks/bank statements, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 288/5)
    - Budget information, 1952 (Box-folder 288/6)
    - Receipts, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 288/7)
  - Martha Graham Center of Contemporary Dance (Box 289)
    - Checkbook/stubs, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 289/1)
    - Checkbook/stubs, 1953 (Box-folder 289/2)
  - Martha Graham Dance Company and Martha Graham School of Contemporary Dance (Box 285)
    - Receipts (MGSCD), 1960 (Box-folder 285/1)
    - Auditor’s report for 1965 (MGDC) (Box-folder 285/2)
    - Payroll, 1965 New York season (Box-folder 285/3)
    - Purchase orders for 1965 New York season (Box-folder 285/4)
  - B. de Rothschild Foundation (Box 284-286, 292)
    - Miscellaneous budget notes and petty cash summary, 1965 (Box-folder 285/5)
    - Purchase orders for 1965 New York season (Box-folder 285/6-7)
    - Purchase orders for 1965 New York season (Box-folder 286/1-2)
    - Income/expense statement (MGSCD), 1965 (Box-folder 286/3)
    - Payroll (MGDC), 1966 (Box-folder 286/4)
    - Martha Graham Foundation checkbook, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 286/5)
    - Petty cash (MGDC), 1969 (Box-folder 286/6)
    - Ledger, 1968 (Box 284)
    - Ledger, (MGDC/MGSCD), 1969 August 1-1970 July 31 (Box 291)
    - Checkbook/stubs (MGSCD), 1969 July-1970 August (Box-folder 292/1)
    - Checkbook/stubs (MGDC), 1969 March-1970 June (Box-folder 292/2)
    - Checkbook/stubs (MGSDC), 1969-1970 (Box-folder 292/3)
  - Martha Graham Dance Company (Box 290)
    - Checkbook/stubs (MGDC), 1968-1969 (Box-folder 290/1)
    - Checkbook/stubs (MGDC), 1967-1968 (Box-folder 290/2)
  - Martha Graham Dance Company and Martha Graham School of Contemporary Dance (Box 292)
    - Ledger, 1970 August 1-1971 July 31 (Box 292)
  - Martha Graham Center of Contemporary Dance (MGCCD) and Martha Graham School of Contemporary Dance (MGSCD), 1970-1973 (Box 294)
    - Checkbook/stubs (for National Endowment grant), 1970 (Box-folder 294/1)
    - Checkbook/stubs (MGCCD), 1970 August 1-1972 January 20 (Box-folder 294/2)
    - Checkbook/stubs (MGCCD), 1970 August 17-1970 October 23 (Box-folder 294/3)
    - Checkbook/stubs (MGCCD), 1970 June 24-1971 January 28 (Box-folder 294/4)
    - Checkbook/stubs (MGSCD), 1970 September 22-1972 May 16 (Box-folder 294/5)
    - Checkbook/stubs (MGCCD), 1970 October 23 -1971 January 18 (Box-folder 294/6)
    - Checkbook/stubs (MGCCD), 1970 November 26-1970 December 2 (Box-folder 294/7)
    - Checkbook/stubs (MGCCD), 1970 January 1-1973 April 23 (Box-folder 294/8)
    - Miscellaneous receipts (MGSCD), 1971-1973 (Box-folder 294/9)
  - Martha Graham Center of Contemporary Dance (MGCCD) and Martha Graham School of Contemporary Dance (MGSCD), 1971-1972 (Box 295)
    - Ledger (MGCCD/MGSCD), 1971 August 1-1972 July 31 Receipts/certificates of deposit, 1971-1972 Payroll ledger (MGCCD/MGSCD), 1971 Payroll ledger (MGCCD/MGSCD), 1972 (Box 295)
  - Martha Graham Center of Contemporary Dance and Martha Graham School of Contemporary Dance, 1972-1973 (Box 293)
    - Checkbook/stubs (MGCCD), 1972 January 24-1973 July 19 (Box-folder 293/1)
    - Petty cash receipts, 1972 (Box-folder 293/2)
    - Charities registration, State of New York, 1973 Ledger (MGCCD/MGSCD), 1972 August 1-1973 July 31 (Box-folder 293/3)
  - Martha Graham Center of Contemporary Dance (Box 296)
    - Financial information, 1973; 1975; 1980; 1982-1983; 1985-1986 Cumulative ledger (MGCCD), 1 January 1987-31 December 1987 (Box-folder 296/1)
  - Martha Graham School of Contemporary Dance and Martha Graham Center of Contemporary Dance—Tax Information (Box 297)
    - Tax liabilities (MGSCD/MGCCD), 1986 (Box-folder 297/1)
    - State/city taxes, New York, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 297/2)
    - New York Department of Labor, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 297/3)
    - Quarterly tax return (MGSCD), 1984 (Box-folder 297/4)
    - Monthly returns (MGSCD), 1984 (Box-folder 297/5)
    - Sales and use tax, 1984 (Box-folder 297/6)
    - Quarterly federal tax (MGCCD), 1984 (Box-folder 297/7)
    - State/city taxes, New York (MGCCD), 1984 (Box-folder 297/8)
    - Quarterly wage report, 1984 (Box-folder 297/9)
    - Unpaid tax file, 1986 (Box-folder 297/10)
    - Unpaid tax file, 1987 (Box-folder 297/11)
  - Martha Graham Center of Contemporary Dance, 1984-1988 (Box 298)
    - Earned income receipts, 1985-1986 Unearned income receipts, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 298/1)
    - Tax returns, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 298/2)
    - Year end processing for annual information, 1988 (Box-folder 298/3)
    - 1099 reports, 1988 (Box-folder 298/4)
    - Payroll charges breakdown, 1988 (Box-folder 298/5)
  - Martha Graham Center of Contemporary Dance (Box 299)
    - Balance sheets/Cash flow, 1988 (Box-folder 299/1)
    - Petty cash receipts, 1988 (Box-folder 299/2)
    - Chemical Bank, 1988 (Box-folder 299/3)
    - W2 forms, 1988 (Box-folder 299/4)
    - Tax account/Debit slips, 1988 (Box-folder 299/5)
  - Martha Graham Center of Contemporary Dance—Deposits 1988 (Box 300)
    - January 1988 (Box-folder 300/1)
    - February 1988 (Box-folder 300/2)
    - March 1988 (Box-folder 300/3)
    - April 1988 (Box-folder 300/4)
    - May 1988 (Box-folder 300/5)
    - June 1988 (Box-folder 300/6)
    - July 1988 (Box-folder 300/7)
    - August 1988 (Box-folder 300/8)
  - Martha Graham Center of Contemporary Dance—Deposits 1988 (Box 301)
    - September 1988 (Box-folder 301/1)
    - October 1988 (Box-folder 301/2)
  - Martha Graham Center of Contemporary Dance—Deposits 1988 (Box 302)
    - November 1988 (Box-folder 302/1)
    - December 1988 (Box-folder 302/2)
  - Martha Graham Center of Contemporary Dance and Martha Graham School of Contemporary Dance, budgets, 1968-1993 (Box 303)
    - 1968; 1970-1971; 1973-1975 (Box-folder 303/1)
    - 1984-1987 (Box-folder 303/2)
    - 1991-1993 (Box-folder 303/3)
  - Martha Graham Center of Contemporary Dance and Martha Graham School of Contemporary Dance, 1989-1990 (Box 304-305)
    - Year end processing, 1990 Ledger, 1989 (Box-folder 304/1)
    - 1990-1996 (Box-folder 305/1)
    - Budgets, 1989 (Box-folder 305/2)
    - Independent auditors report, 1989 (Box-folder 305/3)
- Personal Papers and Finances (Box 276-277)
  The Personal Papers and Finances series contains Graham’s personal papers, receipts, and tax returns. This series is currently restricted.
  - Tax returns, 1948 (Box-folder 276/1)
  - Tax returns, 1955 (Box-folder 276/2)
  - Tax returns, 1957 (Box-folder 276/3)
  - Tax returns, 1958 (Box-folder 276/4)
  - Tax returns, 1959 (Box-folder 276/5)
  - Tax returns, 1960, 1961, 1962, 1966 (Box-folder 276/6)
  - Application for Medicaid, 1966 (Box-folder 276/7)
  - Group insurance benefits, 1984 (Box-folder 276/8)
  - Will of Alice Tully, 1995 (Box-folder 276/9)
  - Address book, undated Date book, 1969 (Box-folder 276/10)
  - Receipts, 1940s (Box-folder 277/1)
  - Receipts, 1950s; 1960s (Box-folder 277/2)
  - Receipts, 1970s (Box-folder 277/3)
  - Receipts, 1970s (Box-folder 277/4)
  - Receipts, 1970s (Box-folder 277/5)
  - Receipts, 1988; undated (Box-folder 277/6)
- Realia (Box 389-397)
  The Realia series contains a collection of awards, plaques, statues, honorary degrees, and other ephemera that honors the achievements of Martha Graham.
  - Awards and Honorary Degrees (Box 389-395)
    - To: Martha Graham, guide and mentor of Batsheva Dance Company. From: America-Israel Cultural Foundation, New York, 1970 December 8, Plexiglas (piece missing?) (Box 389)
    - To: Martha Graham, Woman of Achievement, ADL, 1975 November 13, Plexiglas; artist: Millicent Zahn (Box 389)
    - To: Martha Graham, National Treasure. From: Family Weekly Magazine, 1983, Plexiglas base, with sterling silver plaque (damaged, separated from base) (Box 389)
    - To: Martha Graham, Woman of Accomplishment. From: Harper’s Bazaar, 1967, Plexiglas egg (Box 389)
    - To: Martha Graham for Outstanding Achievement in the Arts. From: North Shore Community Arts Center, 1966 Annual Award, Bronze with plaque detached (base in poor condition) (Box 389)
    - To: Martha Graham, Award of Merit. From: The Lotos Club, 1967 January 24, Plexiglas (Box 390)
    - “Frontier.” From: unknown, 1989, Bronze on marble base; artist: Beau Gage (Box 390)
    - To: Martha Graham. From: Studio Vandoni Premio Porselli “un a vita per la danza,” 1987, Bronze, marble base (Box 390)
    - To: Martha Graham. Meadows Award for Excellence in the Arts, 1989, Marble (Box 390)
    - Unknown, Blue plastic on marble base, inscription plaque missing (Box 390)
    - To: Martha Graham, Centennial Achievement Award for Achieving Excellence in the Arts, Metropolitan Opera House. From: Local One, I.A.T.S.E., 1986 June 15, Plexiglas on wood base (separated) (Box 391)
    - To: Martha Graham, Ethel M. Barber Visiting Artist. From: Northwestern University, the Tribute Year, October 30 – November 5 [no year], Bronze medallion; wood and glass frame (Box 391)
    - To: Martha Graham. An ancient shepherd’s flute to which maidens danced in Biblical times. From: In friendship, Teddy Kolieck. Jerusalem, 1974 July 4, Flute in glass and wood box (Box 391)
    - To: Martha Graham, For an Extraordinary Lifetime of Contribution to American Culture Through the Performing Arts. From: John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts, 1979 December 2, Brass bars attached to multicolored ribbons and reception program in wood box with Plexiglas top (Box 391)
    - To: Martha Graham. From: Honor America and Boehm present the American Bald Eagle plate to honor America and Commemorate our Bicentennial, Porcelain plate in blue box; artist: Adapted from the porcelain sculpture of Edward Marshall Boehm (Box 392)
    - To: Martha Graham. From: The Chattanooga Welcoming Committee, Award of Welcome, Wood plaque (Box 392)
    - To: Martha Graham, The American-Israel Award for the Arts, Sciences and Industry, New York City. From: The Israel Prime Minister’s Club, 1979 March 9, Stainless steel on wood (Box 392)
    - Daily Telegraph and Morning Post “World’s Best Dance Film,” 1959 October 15, Framed enlargement of article on wood (Box 392)
    - To: Martha Graham. From: Office of the Mayor, City of Tucson, Arizona. Certificate of Appreciation, 1988 November 7, Copper paper in wood and glass frame (Box 392)
    - Japanese Award, undated, Star on red, white, blue ribbon in velvet box (Box 392)
    - Three brass medals. Il sindaco di Firenze, undated, Contained in red leather box (Box 392)
    - To: Martha Graham, Honored for her contributions to the world of dance, New York City Dance Showcase IV. From: New York State Association for Health, Physical Education, Recreation, and Dance (NYSAHPERD), 1991 May 29, Brass plaque on wood (Box 392)
    - Aaron Copland and Martha Graham; photo by Bill Cunningham, Plaque on aluminum on wood (Box 392)
    - To: Martha Graham, High Priestess of the Dance. From: DTCB (or DCB), Brass plaque on wood (Box 392)
    - To: Martha Graham. Presidential Medal of Freedom, 10-14-76 Monnaie de Paris, 1976 October 14 (Box 392)
    - To: Martha Graham, to a great artist with great admiration. From: Shlomo Lahat, Mayor of Tel-Aviv-Yato, 1979 August, Brass medal in wooden box (Box 392)
    - Silver commemorative medal (Winston Churchill), Silver medal in leather box (Box 392)
    - Stabilmenti Artistica Fiorentini “Il Sindaco di Firenze” (Box 392)
    - Gold coin in red leather box (Box 392)
    - To: Martha Graham, Distinguished New Yorker Award 1967 on Occasion of the 75th Anniversary of The City Club of New York, 1967, Brass medal in maroon leather case (Box 392)
    - To: Martha Graham, with highest regards. From: Mayor Jonathan Hayes, San Jose, California, Brass and plastic plaque on wood (Box 393)
    - To: Martha Graham, For your dedication and outstanding contribution to dance and the American musical tradition. From: The Hartford Symphony Women’s Auxillary, 1966 September 14, Brass plaque on wood (Box 393)
    - To: Martha Graham. From: Mayor W. Wilson Goode, City of Philadelphia, 1986 October 24, Brass plaque on wood (tray) (Box 393)
    - Management Achievement Award presented to Arizona State University for Martha Graham Dance Company Arizona Residency. From: The Association of College, University and Community Arts Administrators, Inc., 1983 December 18, Brass plaque on wood (Box 393)
    - To: Martha Graham, A Special Distinguished Pennsylvania Artist for more than 70 Years. From: Governor Dick Thornburgh, 1986 November, Brass medal attached to red/black ribbon (Box 393)
    - Brass medal attached to small red/white ribbon, Margareta II Regina Dante (Box 393)
    - To: Martha Graham. Brandeis Book Collections, Brandeis University Library. In Honor of Martha Graham. From: The Cleveland Chapter, Brandeis University National Women’s Committee, undated, Small brown leather booklet with Graham’s name embossed on front (Box 393)
    - To: Martha Graham Dance Company. Premio Positano “L. Massine” per l’arte della danza XXIII Edizione, 3 Settembre 1994, Aluminum plaque on red velvet in black leather box (Box 393)
    - To: Martha Graham. 2 Juillet 1984, Avant Lion Le Melhor, Brass medal in red box (Box 393)
    - To: Martha Graham. Henry Hadley Medal for her service to American music, 1955 May 19, Brass medal in black leather box (Box 393)
    - To: Martha Graham, for her outstanding contributions to the Arts. From: The MacDowell Colony, 1974 November 7, Brass medal in black leather box; artist: Ernest Bruce Haswell, 1916 (Box 393)
    - To: Martha Graham. The Family of Man Award, 1968 October 23, Brass medal in black leather box (Box 393)
    - Commemorative 5 Dollar Coin, Seventh SEAP Games, Singapore, 1973, Coin in green box (Box 393)
    - Commemorative 10 Dollar Coin, Singapore, 1973, Coin in beige box (Box 393)
    - Visite aux Etats-Unis d’Amerique De Monsieur Valéry Giscard d’Estaing, Président de la République Française, 1976 May 17-22, Brass medal in black leather box (Box 393)
    - Camp David Meeting Medal, September 1978, Given to Martha Graham by Frank Nothmann, Public Relations Manager, Jerusalem Hilton, Gold-plated medal in wooden box (Box 393)
    - Olav V Norges Konge, undated, Gold or silver-plated medal attached to red ribbon (Box 393)
    - To: Martha Graham, in recognition of her distinguished career in the theatre by John V. Lindsay, Mayor of the City of New York, 1970 October 2, Brass medal in black leather box; artist: Charlotte Temper Armus (Box 393)
    - To: Martha Graham. Commission Award for Noble Achievement in the Creative Arts, 1968, Brass medal in black leather box (Box 393)
    - Ville de Paris a Martha Graham, 1985, Brass or gold-plated medal in green box (Box 393)
    - Photo of Graham and Bertram Ross, Rendered in metal on wood (Box 393)
    - Award stand (?) inscribed “J. Mesne(?) Brown, 1968”, Plastic laminate on wood (Box 393)
    - Seven-sided Plexiglas paper weight (Box 393)
    - Biennale di Venezia Diploma Speciale al film Dancer’s World, 1958, Copy (Box 394)
    - Honorary Doctorate, Rutgers University, 1959 (Box 394)
    - Laurel Leaf Award. From: American Composers Alliance, [1959] (Box 394)
    - Proclamation by his Excellency Michael S. Dukakis, Governor of the Commonwealth of Massachusetts, 1984 June 21 (Box 394)
    - State of New York, Mario M. Cuomo, Governor, sends congratulations on the occasion of the presentation of the Royal Golden Medal for talent and art by Her Majesty, Queen Margrethe II of Denmark to Martha Graham, 1987 January 14 (Box 394)
    - Orfanatorios Latino American donor certificate to Martha Graham, undated (Box 394)
    - Award of Merit given by The National Association for American Composers and Conductors, 1946-1947 season (musical program included) (Box 394)
    - Govenor’s Citation by Milton J. Sharp, Governor of The Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, 1972 November 15 (Box 394)
    - New School for Social Research Citation of Honor, 1962 September 20 (Box 394)
    - Doctor of Fine Arts, Wesleyan University, 1971 June 6 (Box 394)
    - Doctor of Humane Letters, Arizona State University, 1982 October 17 (Box 394)
    - Doctor of Humane Letters, Marygrove College, 1973 December 2 (Box 394)
    - Doctor of Fine Arts, Smith College, 1969 June 1 (Box 394)
    - Certificate of Appreciation, City of New York, Edward I. Koch, Mayor, 1984 February 28 (Box 394)
    - Presidential Medal of Freedom, Gerald R. Ford, 1976 October 14 (Box 394)
    - Warm regards from Dick Thornburgh, Governor of the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, 1986 November 14 (Box 394)
    - Bravo Award presented by San Antonio Performing Arts Association, San Antonio, Texas, 1983 September 27 (Box 394)
    - Doctor of Humane Letters, Skidmore College, 1978 April 26 (Box 394)
    - Letter of Salutation, Edward I. Koch, Mayor of the City of New York, 1988 May 19 (Box 394)
    - Proclamation from Raymond L. Flynn, Mayor of the City of Boston (declaring October 27, 1989 as “Martha Graham Day”) (Box 394)
    - Scroll of Honor from McKinley Elementary School on the 300th Birthday of the Founding of Pennsylvania (Box 394)
    - The President of the United States (Ronald Reagan) Recognizes Martha Graham, 1985 April 23 (Box 394)